The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you.
Good morning, Church.
(Good morning.)
Viewers, good morning to you all.
Thank you, you may be seated.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I see the need of coming out to wish you Merry Christmas in advance.
The year is coming to an end.
The sooner the better - we begin to remind ourselves what we need to do, preparing for the new year.
Once again - Happy New Year in advance.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let's quickly go to our Holy Bible and see one of the messages the Lord prepared for us for the coming year.
(Amen.)
Take your reading: 1 Corinthians 13.
Thank you - let's take our reading about love here.
1 Corinthians 12:31: "Love is Indispensable
...And yet I will show you the most excellent way."
The most excellent way to enjoy your life.
THE BEAUTY OF LIFE
If I speak in the tongues of men or of angels, but do not have love,
I am only a resounding gong or a clanging cymbal.
If I have the gift of prophecy and can fathom all mysteries and all knowledge,
and if I have a faith that can move mountains, but do not have love, I am nothing.
If I give all I possess to the poor and give my body to hardship...
Many of us fast and pray in hardship - you say, "In the name of Jesus" - listen what the Bible says here:
... that I may boast, but do not have love, I gain nothing.
We fast, we pray but it seems that nothing comes.
Love is patient, love is kind. It does not envy, it does not boast - that is love.
It is not proud, arrogant.
It does not dishonor others, it is not self-seeking - that is love.
It is not easily angered, it keeps no record of wrongs.
Past is past.
Love does not delight in evil but rejoices with the truth.
It puts everything behind - that is love.
‘Let love lead’, that is our motto.
I know many of you have the sticker.
You have it, don't you?
Let love lead.
Let's quickly have a look at 1 Corinthians 13:13:
"And now these three remain: faith, hope and love. But the greatest of these is love."
Let someone say, "Let love lead".
(Let love lead.)
Yes.
If love is the greatest, you should let it lead you everywhere, day by day – love.
Most of us here, we always wait until people are crying for help before we can help.
What the Bible was saying about our attitude towards love, the way and manner we show love?
People crying for help before you can help.
We remain indifferent until people say, “Please, help me!”
We see them lamenting and crying before we say, “Come”.
That is not love.
Such love cannot attract God’s attention.
"Uncle, please help me..."
Where were you looking, before someone came asking, "Help me, uncle"?
You must have seen him in one way or another.
That is not love that attracts God's attention.
What we give or what we do is not as important as the manner and way in which we do it.
What you give me is not as important as the manner and way you give me.
The manner and way you give me attracts God’s attention.
It is not what you give that attracts God’s attention.
It is not the millions you are giving; it is not all your possessions you give
but the manner and way you give them that attracts God’s attention.
When you give to someone in a way that pleases God, someone is waiting to give you too.
When you give to someone in a way that pleases God, someone will be waiting also to give you too.
You have been giving all this...
If you do not give in a way and manner that pleases God, you are just wasting your effort and time.
It is not what we give that matters but the manner and way we give them.
Look at you: you are sitting in the church today.
If there was an issue of big importance to address, who knows if you would be here.
The way you do things attracts God’s attention; it is not what you do.
Who knows – if you received a phone call now:
“Hello” – oh this is my excellency, my president,
this is a million dollar opportunity - who knows if you wouldn't escape the church?
The manner and the way we do things and give things matters.
God is not one of those things – He is the only thing.
The beauty of life does not depend on how happy you are
but on how happy others can be because of you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How many people are happy because of you today?
How many lives have you touched?
Somebody needs something you possess.
It may be your love, smile – a genuine one,
it may be your money, strength, time.
You talk of salvation?
Look at the whole world.
80% of the world is crying - hardship in your place, poverty, orphans which were supposed to go to school -
and you are telling me that you are saved.
Someone is in need of you.
No matter how little you have.
You say you are saved, born again - but see the people on the streets, at your place.
Your children are in the school, but the children of your neighbor are on the street and you turn your head away.
And you say you are saved - salvation.
How do we define salvation?
You may say you are poor; you may be surprised to see someone who is poorer than you are.
In life, there are always greater and lesser people than you.
Let us see the help of the widow, needy, poor, refugee as a priority over any other help.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you help them, you sow to the Spirit.
You are a spirit being.
The real thing about you is not your body.
In John 8:36, Jesus said, ‘If the Son sets you free, you are free indeed’.
He meant the liberation of the spirit man.
He meant the liberation of what?
Spirit man.
A man is a spirit being.
Tell your neighbour, ‘You are a spirit being’.
(You are a spirit being.)
I can't hear you.
Yes.
Let's sow to the Spirit.
For those of us who are saying, ‘I am poor. I have little’,
if you cannot part with little, you will not be able to part with much.
Our idea of "if only" keeps robbing us of our blessings.
If only I had money I would help the poor,
if only I had enough money I would build an orphanage.
The danger here is:
if you fail to help with the little God has blessed you with, more may never come.
The danger here is, if you fail to bless, help people with the little God blessed you with,
more may never come.
That is the measure.
The way and manner you manage little possessions or money,
will make God decide whether to promote you or not.
How do you manage your little possessions?
Everyone claims to have little.
THE BEAUTY OF LIFE
Don’t forget, your possessions alone cannot give you contentment -
that is why we are running helter-skelter -
but giving help to the needy, to the poor can.
Happy New Year in advance.
This is the way, the road to the New Year.
Ask Zacchaeus in Luke 19:9
and he would tell you that when he decided to give cheerfully and genuinely to the poor,
Jesus recommended him and said to him that salvation had come to his household.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The word salvation means contentment.
Are you content?
Salvation means what?
It means you are not saved.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I define again: salvation means contentment - to be content.
What others are doing -
I am what God says I am, I have what God says I have and I can do what God says I can do.
That is the meaning of contentment.
Are you content?
You always measure, compare yourself to others.
That is not contentment.
Envy, jealousy...
A road to the new year.
I want to take you back again in summary.
Love is the greatest weapon – let love lead.
What you are giving is not as important as the way and manner in which you give them.
Tell me - when you have given something to a neighbour and said, "Thank you for receiving my gift"...
When somebody receives your gift, it is reshaping your destiny.
It's helping you.
You are not helping the person you give but the person that receives your gift is helping you.
Today, you believe the person you are giving is the one you are helping and he should thank you.
Rather, you should thank him for receiving your gift.
When you give, you are reshaping your destiny.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
With all your heart, give what is pure, what is good, what is just, what is admirable.
This is why your millions don't give you peace.
You are supposed to realise peace and comfort but yet, no peace, no comfort
upon your possessions and money because you have not been giving
to the poor, needy, refugees, widows and orphans in a manner and way that pleases God.
When you give with all your heart, someone is waiting to give to you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If I remind you about tithes, offerings - I am not supposed to say it.
If I say and you give me, it will not bless me, because you are not giving this from your heart.
It is not something they should inform or remind me about.
It should come from your heart.
There is no forcing in it.
It is a blessing.
We don’t force people to bless; blessing comes naturally.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you are not giving to the needy with all your heart, you are just wasting your time.
Yes.
Let the Spirit convince you.
Happy New Year in advance.
If you have two shirts, give one to the poor.
If you have food, share with those who are hungry.
Go into your wardrobe, go into your cupboard, go into your store
and see the need to give to the needy and the poor.
Your life will not remain the same.
(Amen.)
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I want to see you going to the bank, withdrawing the money and giving it to the poor.
THE BEAUTY OF LIFE
Don't wait for the reward after giving.
It is better they don't know you.
If they know you, don’t pose yourself as a giver. Jesus is the Giver.
(Amen.)
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I am giving you the picture of my life.
Your labour of love without cheerful and sincere giving cannot help you.
Let us be sincere to ourselves; stop giving only what you do not need.
Give also what you need.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If God had been giving you what you do not need, would you be blessed?
You give what you do not need.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour, "Stop giving only what you do not need".
(Stop giving only what you do not need.)
Giving is a sacrifice.
If you give what you do not need, that is not sacrifice.
Sacrifice means pain in one way or the other.
You feel it, you must feel it...
Look at the time you come here.
It seems to apply to many of us here.
Time you don't actually need - there is nothing to do out there: no job, no game, nothing -
"What would I do at home? Let me go to church."
You should commit not only the time you don't need.
You should be part of your church - not only attending the Sunday service.
You should ask, "What can I do? Look at the church - it is very clean. Who cleaned it?
Will I just come and sit? No! I must join the department".
Once a week - find a day to help the department in what they do.
Join an evangelical department - it is your home.
Money, money, money - no!
Money cannot bring contentment but giving it to help the poor can.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, New Year is coming.
There is no other way to prepare for the New Year.
The best way is to allow love to lead.
If love must lead you, you must consider the way and manner you do things,
the way and manner you give things,
the way and manner you sleep,
the way and manner you sit,
the way and manner you look,
the way and manner you dress,
the way and manner you walk,
the way and manner you greet,
the way and manner you do things you must consider – that is love.
In a manner that pleases God, that is what we call love.
Not to just give, help - but the manner you help, give or greet.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Rise up, let’s lift up our voice to God, to help us serve Him with all our talent
because we have not been serving God with all our talent.
The manner and way we serve God with our talent, our love is not pleasing to Him.
Open your lips, ask God, “Help me to serve You with all my talent – my labour of love”.
Prayer!
I want to serve You Lord with all my talent!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In Jesus Christ’s name, we pray.
(Amen.)
Yes.
You are here today - this is not your quality time that you give to God.
Many of you will come here next Sunday again.
That's all.
That is the way you serve God.
Ask Him, "Lord, Your grace in this coming year."
You have to prepare now for the New Year.
This is the way to prepare.
You have to realise your mistakes - this is what you need to do right, now.
My talent, my gift - about people, about God.
Ask Him, "Lord Jesus, give me the grace to serve You with all my talent, my love, my time.”
Prayer!
You need grace.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In Jesus Christ’s name we pray.
(Amen.)
Ask Him, ”Help cleanse all my wrongs in action and thoughts, knowingly and unknowingly”.
Prayer!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In Jesus Christ’s name we pray.
(Amen.)
The SCOAN Sunday Service